My husband is hostile
and stingy toward my family.
I hesitated a few times but I came to
ask you a question about my husband.
We've been married for 2 years
with no kids and we both work.
My husband is overly hostile
and stingy toward my family.
Though I am the youngest of three
children, I always helped my parents.
I helped with the living expenses at home
before I got married.
I contributed over 1/3 of the expenses and
thought that it was my duty as an offspring.
But my in-laws believe that daughters
have no financial obligations.
So, when something big comes up,
my husband takes care of it.
My family is different but I accepted
it knowing that we can afford it.
Since we both work, we paid for his
father's hospital bills among other things
I didn't mind too much.
My mother-in-law said
she never got anything from her son
before we got married.
But since I came, she is receiving help
from her son and is grateful to me.
The problem is
my husband doesn't want to offer
any financial help to his in-laws.
Recently, my parents were planning a trip.
I suggested that my mother-in-law join
them since she has never been abroad.
While we paid for his mother's expenses
and gave her spending money,
my husband flatly refused to pay
for his in-laws expenses.
He says
he is willing to help his own mother,
but he sternly refuses to help my parents
even if he had the money.
I work just as hard and
contribute to the family finances.
When his father was hospitalized,
I helped even though
we were rather hard up.
But when my mother
needed to have a surgery,
he didn't even offer to help one bit.
The bill wasn't that much at the time
and knowing that he didn't want to help,
I let it pass but it always bothered me
that we didn't do our duty as children.
Furthermore, he criticized my mom
for wanting to take the trip
in the midst of poor finances.
He often complains about my family
and criticizes my brother for not working.
He criticizes my family for putting
the burden on the married daughter.
He is unfair
and barely does minimum for my family.
I have a hard time dealing with
such a stingy husband.
He does give a little money on birthdays
or on holidays,
but he firmly refuses
to give any other times.
Because of all kinds of
suppressed feelings from the past,
I feel explosive
and feel turned off by him.
I don't like to argue
so I try not to do things he dislikes.
Should I go along with him
in order to maintain peace in the family
or should I insist on fairness
and argue with him?
My husband is rather stubborn
and has a short temper.
I am waiting to have a surgery
for thyroid cancer
so it is not good for me to be arguing
and getting upset.
I am trying to just adjust
and avoiding conflict.
He is acting with no concern
knowing full well how I feel.
I am feeling more alienated and resentful
by his friendly talks and calls.
I would like to ask your advice on
how to deal with him
and how to understand him.
(Sunim) Do you work?
(Questioner) Yes.
(Sunim) Why not just give
some money to your parents
out of your salary
without telling the husband?
(Questioner) I suppose I could do that.
But I feel it's somewhat disgraceful.
That's not disgraceful...
(Questioner) If my husband finds out,
he may get upset...
Considering his family and his background,
for instance,
if his mother takes a trip or is sick,
do the daughters come to help
or give her money?
(Questioner) The daughters
do not contribute.
To their family?
(Questioner) Right.
That's how he grew up.
So he wonders why you, a married daughter,
should bother with your family.
You married into this family,
then you are part of this family.
They are rather traditionalists.
Do you understand?
But you grew up thinking that you ought to
help support your parents and you
naturally want to continue doing that
believing that it's your duty.
You have different backgrounds.
So, what should you do
to go on living together?
It's not that he is bad or stingy.
It's not about money even.
He wonders why you should help
even after you're married.
He believes it's your brother's job,
not yours.
It's not that he is a bad person.
Let's just say he is old-fashioned.
How come you married such a guy?
(Audience Laughter)
Since he's been accustomed to
thinking this way all his life,
it's hard to change his ways;
he can't be changed overnight.
So, don't try to change him.
But first, aside from this,
is he okay to live with?
(Questioner) He is not a bad person.
(Sunim) Aside from this issue
with his in-laws, he is okay?
Yes.
(Sunim) Are you going to leave
or stay over this issue?
(Audience Laughter)
I am not considering
such extreme case of leaving or not.
He seems okay with it but I am...
So, tell me first whether you're
going to leave or stay with him.
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) I will stay.
If you keep making this an issue,
you will feel hatred toward him.
Who is going to suffer
if you live with hatred?
(Questioner) I'm the one,
who is going to suffer
Unless you're going to leave him,
even if you insist your ways,
will he change or not?
I don't think he can change.
(Sunim) Right.
(Sunim) But if you keep trying though,
you will end up hating him, no?
Hating him will cause you to suffer.
Good thing you don't have any kids yet.
If a mother is unhappy
and hates her husband,
the baby will be anxious taking after mom.
The baby will have anxiety
and hatred will take root.
(Sunim) This is not good.
(Sunim) You can leave but if you're
staying, follow your husband's way.
Cut the ties with your family
since you're married now.
(Questioner Laughter)
(Sunim) You think your parents would want
you to continue helping them in spite of
it causing you a marriage problem
and you moving back home?
Won't they prefer that you be happy
even though you can't help them out?
(Questioner) My parents don't expect
any help.
So, why then?
Why do you create problems
when they don't even expect anything?
Don't do it
if your husband doesn't like it.
You must stop it right now.
If not, you are asking for trouble.
This is not about who is right or wrong.
You have different family cultures.
Understand?
(Sunim) Since you're married,
it's better to adjust to your husband.
(Sunim) Drop your idea of fairness here.
Then, you will have a better relationship.
(Sunim) And you will raise a happy child.
(Sunim) If you have a baby
in this state of mind,
your baby will not fare well.
Are you going to stop now?
(Questioner) Yes, I will do that.
(Sunim) Don't just say it. You must do it.
(Sunim) Think of yourself as newly
married today.
Resolve this now. Okay?
(Questioner) Yes.
Once in a while,
when you want to give some spending money,
you can use bonuses
or something that he wouldn't know about.
(Audience Laughter)
You could come into money sometimes, no?
Give some money once in a while.
Tell him you're buying a dress but
you can give a little
when you visit your mom sometime.
No need to be a big sum. You know?
And it's not such a good thing for
parents to receive money from daughters.
How many siblings do you have?
(Questioner) There are three of us.
How many sons?
(Questioner) One.
Younger sister then?
(Questioner) I have
an older sister.
Leave it up to your brother.
And cut the ties.
You live a happy life.
That is real filial duty to your parents.
Giving them money
is not fulfilling filial duty.
It's difficult for your husband to change.
But it's not because he is a bad person.
That's his background. That is why.
So, use your charm.
Say, "You are right"
"But she is still my mom.
So can we give 1/10 at least?"
You know with a sweet smile, for example.
(Audience Laughter)
They say that a woman can persuade a man
to give over his liver.
(Audience Laughter)
Can't you do that?
Don't try to win by arguing.
Be sweet and take over his liver, OK?
(Questioner) Yes, I will try my best
to persuade with sweet smiles.
That's right.
(Applause)